fabfilter.com 2019-06-16

# FabFilter - Privacy policy

We know that you care how your personal data is used and shared with others. We appreciate your trust in us and will handle your personal data carefully and sensibly. This statement describes our privacy policy and informs you of the ways we use your personal data. By visiting and using our website and the services we provide to you, you accept and consent to the practices described in this statement, hereafter referred to as "Privacy Policy". 

## Controller of personal information

Any personal data (according to article 4 of the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR")) provided to or gathered by us shall be solely controlled by us according to our activities as data controller and be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You can find us at: 

FabFilter V.O.F. 

Keizersgracht 467

1017 DK Amsterdam

The Netherlands

Chamber of Commerce number: 34204178

VAT identification number: NL8135.59.182.B01

## What personal data do we gather, for which purposes and on which grounds?

The personal data we gather from you as our customer helps us personalize and continually improve your shopping experience at our website. We use your personal data to deliver services such as software updates and bug fixes, communicate with you about our promotional offers, update our records and maintain your account(s) with us, display content such as purchased license keys and recommend services that might be of interest to you. We use your personal data for the following purposes (i) to be able to service the agreement we have with you, (ii) to improve our website, prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our website and (iii) enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions. In this Privacy Policy we will lay down the specific processing of your personal data for the specific purposes we have defined as well as how you can control the personal data we store about you. Here are the types of information we gather: 

  * #### Your FabFilter account

After you have made a purchase via the web shop or entered an activation code at our website, FabFilter will automatically create a personal account for you. This personal account contains the following information: first name, last name, address, zip, phone, e-mail address, (un)subscription for newsletters, a purchase overview and tell-a-friend credit, hereinafter referred to as "Account Information". 

If you have made a purchase in the web shop, you have entered into an agreement with Cleverbridge AG, a company that is licensed to sell our product to you. They collect information from you to handle your orders, deliver services to you, process payments, communicate with you about orders, respond to your requests, customise your future shopping for you, improve the store, and communicate with you. The information they collect consists of the information that you enter into their website. For further explanation and information please read the [Cleverbridge Privacy Policy](https://www.cleverbridge.com/corporate/privacy-policy/). In this policy you will find that they will share certain personal data about you with us. This personal data is made part of your Account Information. You can control your Account Information at any time. 

We only use the Account Information that you provide or we have received through Cleverbridge AG for the following purposes: (i) delivering our services you wish to receive, (ii) responding to your requests, (iii) improving our website, and (iv) communicating with you (v) verifying your identity as part of our proceedings to protect your personal data. 

We process Account Information on the grounds of necessity for the performance of the contract we have with you, or you wish to enter into with us. 

For the avoidance of doubt, if you have requested to receive our newsletter, but have never purchased a product with us, we do not create an account for you, and this paragraph is not applicable to you. 

  * #### Your interaction on our website

We receive and store information and personal data from you when you interact with us through our website. The information and personal data concerned are: your IP (Internet protocol) address, your computer and browser type and version, your login attempts, your search queries, and other browsing activities on our website relevant to monitor the function(s) of our website, hereinafter referred to as "Automatic Information". We use the Automatic Information for the purpose of (i) delivering our services you wish to receive and (ii) improving our website. We collect your IP address, to track technical issues and errors so we are able to improve our website. We use your IP address and log activities to be able to avoid or eliminate fraudulent use of your account. This way we can – for example – see if there is an irregular amount of login attempts on your account. This may indicate fraud. In such an instance we may request you to verify your identity using your Account Information. We store your IP address and your activities on our website for this purpose in our logs for a maximum of seven days. You may always contact us if you wish to delete this information and/or personal data from our files. 

We process Automatic Information on the grounds of necessity for the performance of the contract we have with you, or you wish to enter into with us as well as the grounds of the necessity of legitimate interests pursued by us and you, being the avoidance of fraud. 

  * #### E-mail communications

If you have an account with us, or if you have subscribed to receive our newsletter, we will use your e-mail address to send you e-mails concerning our promotional offers, unless you choose not to receive such e-mails anymore by unsubscribing yourself for this service in your account or by clicking at the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of a promotional e-mail message. You will not receive these promotional e-mails anymore after you have unsubscribed. 

When you have subscribed to our newsletter via our website, we may process your email address on the grounds of the necessity of performing your request to receive our newsletter and on the grounds of your consent. When you have purchased a product from us, we use your e-mail address on the grounds of the necessity of our legitimate interests to inform you on our new products, promotions and updates. As we give you the opportunity to unsubscribe whenever you would want to, we feel we have taken your interests into account. 

The web shop for our merchandise is serviced by sprd.net AG. They collect personal data from you to handle your orders, deliver services to you, process payments, and communicate with you about orders respond to your requests. For further explanation and information please read the [sprd.net AG Privacy Policy](https://www.spreadshirt.com/privacy-policy-C3259). Sprd.net AG does _not_ share any personal data about you with us. 

## How secure is information about me?

We have implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures in such a manner that all processing of your personal data will meet the requirements by law and ensure the protection of your rights. However such protection can unfortunately not be guaranteed, as no system available is one hundred percent safe. We work to protect the security of your personal data during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information and the personal data you input. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of personal data. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you. It is important for you to protect against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer, and to not use the "Keep me logged in on this device" login feature in this case. 

Our computers are safeguarded by long and complex passwords. Our servers are physically situated in the Netherlands and serviced by a Dutch company. Our physical office can only be entered by authorized personnel. Visitors can only enter the building that our office is situated in, after being given access by authorized personnel. We have created access profiles for our employees giving them limited access to our systems and (personal) data actually needed to perform their work. 

Your privacy is of continuous importance to us, meaning we will evaluate our privacy policy frequently and are open to improvement and discussions. 

## What information can I access and control?

You can chose not to provide us certain personal data, such as your zip code. Not providing us with certain data may render us unable to fully assist you. We might – for example – need more personal data to verify your identity when you have lost your password. 

We give you access to the personal data that we keep about you and a broad range of information about your account and your interactions with us for the purpose of viewing and updating or changing that information. This concerns the following personal data: your address, e-mail address, subscription to newsletter, an overview of historical purchases (via which you can view your purchased license keys), and the amount of credit you received by using the tell-a-friend feature. You can add or update certain information on your FabFilter account. You may alter your subscription to the newsletter yourselves as well as the possibility to view your historical purchases and associated license keys. If you don't want to receive e-mail or other mail from us, please adjust this preference in your FabFilter account or use the unsubscribe link that is placed at the bottom of every (promotional) e-mail of FabFilter you will receive. 

Certain updates and changes to Account Information are – for your safety - carefully controlled by us and may for that reason not always be made by yourselves. We will be available to assist you with such changes. Changes to your personal data shall be made in cooperation with us, to make sure such changes are correct and are not requested by anyone else but yourselves. 

You cannot delete your personal FabFilter account yourself. However, if you request us to do so, we will delete your account for you. 

If you wish to receive an even more detailed list of the personal data we use and store about you, please contact us and we will inform you accordingly. If such an overview would not be sufficient to you, please let us know, and we will inform you even more specifically where needed. 

## Do we share the information we receive?

Information about our customers and their personal data is an important part of our business and we are _not_ in the business of selling it to others. We share your personal data only as described below and with the subsidiaries that are either subject to this Privacy Policy or follow practices at least as protective as those described in this Privacy Policy. 

  * #### Third-party service providers

We work together with Cleverbridge AG to handle sales through the/our web shop. They only have access to personal information they collected from you themselves. They process the personal information in accordance with their own Privacy Policy and as permitted by applicable data protection laws. 

We use two software systems to communicate through e-mail. All e-mails automatically generated by our website (such as the e-mails you receive when you create an account or our newsletters) are services through a program called Mandrill, that is part of the platform MailChimp. MailChimp is owned and controlled by The Rocket Science Group LLC, located in the USA. MailChimp participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. 

The second software system we use concerns our support e-mail communication. The program facilitating this service is called Manuscript owned and controlled by Fogcreek Software Inc. Fog Creek complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. Fog Creek has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. 

  * #### Protection of FabFilter and others

We release Account Information and other personal data when we believe release is necessary to comply with the law; enforce or apply agreed terms or agreements; or protect the rights, property or safety of FabFilter, our users or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organisations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Obviously, however, this does not include selling, renting, sharing or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in a way that is contrary to the commitments made in this Privacy Policy. 

  * #### With your consent

Other than as set out above, you will receive a specified notice before your personal data may be shared with third parties giving you the opportunity to inform us that you wish us not to share this personal data, after which we will abstain from doing so. If you choose to consent to the transfer of data, you may at any time retract your consent and we will cease sharing your personal data immediately. 

  * #### Transfer outside the European Economic Area

Whenever we transfer personal information to countries outside of the European Economic Area in the course of sharing information as set out above, we will ensure that the information is transferred in accordance with this Privacy Policy and as permitted by the applicable laws on data protection. 

## Are children allowed to use the FabFilter website?

FabFilter doesn't sell services for purchase by children. If you're under 18, you may use the FabFilter website only with the involvement of a parent or guardian. 

## What about cookies?

Cookies are small text files that we transfer to your device to enable our systems to uniquely identify your device. We use functional cookies, and analytic cookies by a third-party (Google Analytics). The cookies we use have limited effect on your privacy, meaning we are not required to request your approval to place such cookies while you visit our website. However, if you have any questions about the cookies we use, please contact us and we will answer your queries. The FabFilter website uses the following types of cookies: 

  * #### Functional cookies

These cookies improve the user experience on our website. We use them to identify you when you want to sign in to our site, so you don't have to enter your login details again. Also, we use a cookie to remember whether we have asked you to subscribe to our newsletter after downloading software from our website. 

  * #### Analytic third-party cookies

We use Google Analytics, which will transfer cookies to your device. We use the (anonymous) information gathered by Google Analytics to improve FabFilter's content and services. We have altered the functionalities of Google Analytics in accordance with the published 'privacy friendly' manner published and approved by the Dutch Data Protection Authority (Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens). This means that we have entered into a processing agreement with Google, that the last digits of your IP address are encrypted, that we do not use the facility by Google to share IP addresses and that we do not use any other services by Google in combination with Google Analytics. We recommend you to read [Google's privacy policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en-GB/policies/privacy/) carefully if you wish to make yourself familiar with the specifics of their services. 

The "Help" feature on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on's settings or visiting the website of its manufacturer. 

## Our policy concerning personal data breaches

When a personal data breach is likely to result in a high risk to your rights and freedoms, or is otherwise required by law, or when we feel this is appropriate, we will communicate such a personal data breach to you without undue delay. Such a notification shall describe in clear and plain language the nature of the personal data breach contains and shall at least give you the following information and measures: (a) the name and contact details of the data protection officer or other contact point where more information can be obtained; (b) describe the likely consequences of the personal data breach; (c) describe the measures taken or proposed to be taken by the controller to address the personal data breach, including, where appropriate, measures to mitigate its possible adverse effects. 

If required by law, we shall have to inform the Dutch Data Protection Authority of a personal data breach and share any information with this authority as required by law. 

## Conditions of use, notices & revisions

If you have any concern about privacy at FabFilter, please [contact us](mailto:%20info@fabfilter.com) with a thorough description and we will try to resolve the issue for you. If our reply or the solution we have offered you is not sufficient in your opinion, please inform us hereof. Alternatively you may address your complaint about our privacy policy at the Dutch Data Protection Authority ([www.autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl](https://www.autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/)). 

Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. Our business changes constantly and our Privacy Policy will change also. We advise you to check our website frequently to stay updated on possible changes. However, we stand behind the promises we make and will never materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of personal data collected in the past without the prior consent of the customers affected.
